# JERRY HOBBY

Houston, TX 77036 • (713) 298-4862 • Jerry. Hobby@United.com

## **Professional Summary**

Proactive systems analyst with 20+ years of experience in large and small corporate environments. Effective driver of product development lifecycle from concept to delivery. Communicative and collaborative with proven history of improving business operations to support corporate growth and revenue.

Detail-oriented team player with strong organizational skills. Ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously with a high degree of accuracy.

#### Skills

- Business Requirements
- Technical Design
- Process Improvement
- Software Development
- Customer Service

- Technical Expertise
- Communication Skills
- Project Management
- Airline Experience
- Navigator, EZR, SHARES

## **Work History**

## Global Services Reservations Agent, 10/2021 to Current

**United Airlines** – Houston, TX

- Provided high level of customer service to elite customers using active listening and effective interpersonal skills
- Received 20+ orchid letters for delivering above and beyond customer expectations
- Documented over 100 technical issues and suggestions for improvements to Navigator
- Actively involved in Navigator Beta Testing
- Used critical thinking to break down technical problems and make recommendations
- Cultivated interpersonal skills by building positive relationships with others
- Passionate about learning and committed to continual improvement
- Demonstrated high level of initiative and creativity while tackling difficult tasks
- Adaptable and proficient in learning new concepts quickly and efficiently

## **Principal**, 01/2003 to 06/2021

## Texas Business Technologies Dba Anything Internet – Houston, TX

- Designed 20+ business applications and managed technical requirements
- Facilitated communications between technical team and stakeholders
- Consulted on client branding and marketing initiatives
- Managed remote technical staff of 30 engineers in Romania, India, and The Philippines
- Hosted weekly technology radio talk show on CNN radio to promote business technology and marketing strategies

## **Senior Infrastructure Engineer**, 01/1988 to 12/2002

**EDS** – Houston, TX

- Business development for mid-range and mainframe infrastructure projects ranging from \$1M to \$150M total contract value
- Participated in system development life cycle from requirements analysis through system implementation
- Developed proposals for stakeholders outlining project scope and timeline
- Implemented and managed distributed network of over 60 mid-ranged HP-UX systems
- Developed and implemented multiple business systems for Continental Airlines
- Worked closely with customers, internal staff and stakeholders to determine planning, implementation and integration of new applications and infrastructure
- Managed installation, upgrade and deployment projects and provided on-site direction for network engineers
- Managed use of various databases and configured, installed and upgraded new ones
- Supported data center operations with procedures, script writing, and on-call support
- Managed and monitored installed systems for highest level of availability

#### **Education**

**High School Diploma**: 06/1981

Magnolia High School - Magnolia, TX